welcome to the listening Time Podcast
hey everybody this is Connor and you're
listening to episode
133 of the listening Time Podcast I hope
you're all doing excellent and I want to
wish you a Merry Christmas uh around
this time when this episode is released
I think Christmas will be in about a
week uh if I'm not mistaken and that's
actually the topic of today's episode
we're going to talk about Christmas and
specifically what Christmas is like in
the US I'm sure that a lot of you are
interested in this topic uh this is a
really big deal in the US uh the
Christmas season is really
important and uh it's very unique in
this country so I'm happy to talk about
that today I'm sure I've mentioned
certain aspects about Christmas uh in
other episodes but I wanted to do a full
episode dedicated to this topic today so
hopefully it will be interesting and
educational for you and before we start
remember that if you need my help to
understand native speakers when they
speak fast then make sure to join my
membership so you can access my
listening practice seminars where I help
you understand the real sounds of
English uh when people speak at normal
speed so the link is down below in the
episode description that's
patreon.com listening time and of course
if you want my us conversations
podcast uh where I speak to other native
speakers from around the country then
make sure to sign up for that podcast
the link is also down below that's
patreon.com USC
conversations and if you like this
podcast please share it with any other
English Learners that you know and
please give it a five-star rating and
write a review all right let's get
started are your ears ready you know
what time it is it's listening
time okay let's talk about Christmas in
the US first of all I want to mention
that Christmas is usually considered by
most people to be the most important
holiday holiday in the US I already
mentioned this in the episode about
Thanksgiving uh but I want to repeat it
here today uh Thanksgiving is not the
most important holiday in the US uh but
for some reason a lot of uh people from
other countries think this they think
that Thanksgiving is uh the most
important holiday here but most people
would consider Christmas to be the most
important holiday so there are a lot of
reasons for this of course at the Heart
of Christmas is the religious aspect of
the holiday the reason why Christmas
exists right it's to celebrate the birth
of Jesus Christ right so Christians in
the US will really value Christmas
because it's the celebration of the
birth of our Lord and savior right
there's uh a huge reason to celebrate uh
if you're a Christian but even if you're
not religious this holiday is probably
still the most important one throughout
the year uh because it's become a
holiday that most people celebrate uh
whether or not they uh regard the
religious aspect of it so it's still big
uh just in
society um Beyond just uh the religious
population so there is the religious
significance uh the reason for the
holiday
obviously however it's also a really big
holiday for other people and for other
reasons as well and we have a whole
season around Christmas there's the
Christmas season so the whole month of
December uh is special in the US this
month feels different
it looks different it sounds different
uh you can tell that it's the Christmas
season anytime in December and I'll talk
a little more about that in just a
minute um but yeah we have a whole
season around Christmas uh that's how
significant uh this holiday is and of
course it's a really big family holiday
uh usually
this is a day when you get together with
your family and you eat together and you
have this time as a family uh like
Thanksgiving Thanksgiving also has that
aspect as well um but Christmas does too
and for me Christmas has more of that
it's on another level so Christmas is
really
significant uh for uh its family aspect
as well and we have a Christmas culture
I would call it um in the US we have a
whole culture that is related to this
holiday so there are a lot of things
that are specific to Christmas
that suddenly appear around this time of
year and a lot of things become
different and people do different things
they even act differently sometimes
around this season so there's a whole
separate culture when it comes to
Christmas so let me talk a little bit
about that so during the Christmas
season
what happens well first of all let me
talk about when this season is so I
think that technically the Christmas
season starts right after a Thanksgiving
for some people uh the Christmas season
starts even
earlier uh they already get in the
Christmas spirit earlier on in the year
uh however I think that um
for most people after Thanksgiving it's
Christmas time it's the Christmas season
so this starts at the end of November of
course and then it continues on through
December so we have multiple weeks we
have uh a full month where
Everything
feels uh like Christmas
the season is in full swing in English
when we say that something is in full
swing we're saying that you are now in
this period you are in this season it is
happening now completely so by the time
December comes the Christmas season is
in full swing and you you start to see
uh this Christmas culture all around you
so there is the
visual aspect of this Christmas season
so of course the decorations are a big
part of this and Christmas
decorations usually come up after
Thanksgiving and they're taken down in
January you usually at the beginning of
January that's usually when you'll see
these
decorations however sometimes you'll see
them even earlier than that uh and
you'll see them stay up even later than
the beginning of January but uh usually
most people have their decorations up
throughout the month of December
throughout that whole month month and we
have some special areas throughout our
cities uh where we have really really
cool Christmas decorations and Christmas
lights so if you visit the US during the
month of December and you're in a big
city there will probably be multiple
neighborhoods where the whole
neighborhood has really incredible
Christmas
decorations and each neighborhood that
does this has a different nickname a
name for itself so the name might be
Candy Cane Lane or Starlight Circle or
something like that and people will go
from different parts of the city to uh
see this neighborhood and see all of the
decorations and the lights there this is
a really cool tradition that we have in
the US during the month of December I'm
excited to take my family to see some of
these neighborhoods this season and they
sometimes sell
things um in these neighborhoods uh at
night when a lot of people are walking
through the neighborhood they might sell
hot chocolate or cookies or other snacks
it's uh a whole experience when you do
this so that's a really cool thing and
there's also the audio aspect of the
Christmas season I talked about the
visual aspect but the there's also the
audio aspect because there is Christmas
music
everywhere everywhere you turn you hear
Christmas music by the way when we say
everywhere you turn we just mean
everywhere you go everywhere you look
everywhere around you so everywhere you
turn uh there's Christmas music playing
when you walk into a store uh if they
have music at that store chances are
it's Christmas
music and we have a whole genre of music
here called Christmas music uh musical
artists release Christmas albums
specifically for this season so there is
a whole genre dedicated to Christmas
music so that's something that you'll
hear everywhere everywhere you go you
hear Christmas music so it sounds like
Christmas uh during this month and
people watch Christmas
movies uh this is a
genre of movies here in the US we have
Christmas movies there are tons T and
tons of Christmas movies and some
families have the tradition of watching
the same Christmas movie or the same
Christmas movies uh every year and
they've already seen those movies 20
times but they continue to watch them
every year because it's the tradition
during the Christmas season my sister
does this I think uh she watches a lot
of Christmas movies and rewatches them
every year uh I don't really do this but
when I was a kid there were a couple
Christmas movies that I really liked and
I watched them uh year after year so I
participated in that a little bit when I
was is younger and there are Christmas
cards that you see uh in people's houses
uh a Christmas card is a card that you
make by taking a picture uh often times
uh with a professional photographer not
always but sometimes you take a picture
during this season uh with you and your
family and then you create these
Christmas cards and you send these
Christmas cards to your friends and your
family members and some people uh write
something on these Christmas cards uh
some people write uh things about what
each person in their family has done
this year uh they give you an update on
the life of the different family members
some people do that with these cards but
other people just put the names of each
person on the card or maybe they just
put the last name of the family but the
picture is the most important part and
people will put these Christmas cards on
their refrigerator they'll use a magnet
to stick these cards from different
people on their refrigerator or
somewhere else in the house sometimes
and so you can see uh the pictures of
all their different friends and family
members uh there on the fridge so that's
something that
uh really big here in the US but I don't
think that's a big thing in other
countries um but that's another thing uh
that happens during the Christmas season
and uh of course there's the food I
haven't mentioned that but uh the food
uh during the Christmas season is very
particular to Christmas so there are a
lot of
different types of foods that we only
eat during Christmas or during
Thanksgiving and there are a lot of
flavors that change during this season
so certain foods or drinks will have
holiday flavors Christmas flavors during
November and December you'll see a lot
of flavors that incorporate certain
fruits or other things that are related
to this season and there are certain
drinks especially that are like holiday
drinks like eggnog for example uh that's
something that you buy during the
Christmas season uh but not at any other
time during the year so that aspect the
food and the drinks that changes uh and
that becomes Christmassy during this
time and one other thing that also
changes is there's something that we
might call Christmas cheer so cheer
refers to happiness being uh bright and
hopeful and happy and uh Smiley this is
cheer so during this season people might
seem a little bit more cheerful in
public uh people will greet you uh or
they will um say goodbye to you with uh
a Merry Christmas uh or something like
that and you can sometimes feel like
people uh have this cheer and are a
little bit nicer during this time of
year and so that's a good thing as well
that's something nice uh regarding the
Christmas season so as you can see
during the Christmas season you feel
Christmas everywhere you feel it all
around you right and talking
specifically about the days uh December
24th and December
25th uh I also wanted to mention that in
the US Christmas is December 25th
Christmas Eve is what we call December
24th however Christmas day December 25th
this is the day this is the most
important day the 24th is also so very
important however Christmas is December
25th uh in other countries December 24th
is the important day and then the 25th
isn't quite that important however in
the US it's not like this people don't
usually stay up all night on December
24th and um have this big party uh into
the early hours of the morning and then
uh go to bed really really late that's
not the traditional custom in the US
some people might do that but that's not
uh what's uh most common I think most
people really enjoy Christmas Eve and
many people celebrate on that day um
however they probably go to bed at a
normal time and kids usually go to bed
uh fairly early and then people wake up
early on Christmas morning on December
25th uh kids especially uh love waking
up really early on Christmas Day and
going to open their presents that's a
really big tradition in the US so uh
December 24th and December 25th are both
really important however the 25th is
Christmas that is the day that's
Christmas for us so I also just wanted
to mention that and one other thing I
wanted to mention is the weather so if
you live in a place in the US that has
Four
Seasons uh that has a real winter people
often hope for a white Christmas when we
say a white Christmas we're talking
about a Christmas when it snows there's
snow on the ground and it's white so
people really like this in the US uh
because the snow makes it feel like
Christmas I don't live in a city where
it snows so this doesn't exist here but
in other places this is something that
people really like and Christmas feels
like a holiday where you're supposed to
be
inside uh warm with your family uh often
times with a fire in the fire fireplace
uh the fireplace is the part of your
house where you can light a fire and
then the smoke goes up through the
chimney and in the US many people live
in
houses uh versus Apartments of course a
lot of people live in apartments too but
here many many people live in houses uh
more than uh people in a lot of other
countries so here it's common to have a
fireplace and you can light a fire and
feel warm and cozy by the fire with your
family uh drinking uh a warm drink like
hot chocolate or something uh and enjoy
that atmosphere uh that nice environment
and see the snow outside people people
really love that in the US uh again I
don't have that because I live in
Southern California but that's kind of
the Romantic image of Christmas that a
lot of people have so that's Christmas
in the US uh there are many other things
that I didn't mention but I wanted to
give you a feel uh for this season and
and the Christmas culture that we have
and I love Christmas it's my favorite
holiday and for me it's the only thing I
like about the winter season because I
don't like the winter uh it's too cold
for me the days are too short I like the
sun I like being outside I like the warm
weather uh so Christmas is the only
thing that I really look forward to in
the winter uh it's okay if it's a little
bit colder and darker because we have
all the decorations and lights and the
Christmas
atmosphere however when Christmas is
over then I want it to be spring or
summer again but I love Christmas and
I'm looking forward to Christmas this
year okay that's it for today I hope you
enjoyed this episode remember that if
you need my help understanding native
speakers when they speak fast make sure
to join my membership so you can get my
listening training the link is down
below that's patreon.com/crashcourse
and if you like this podcast please
share it and please write a review and
give it a five-star rating and I want to
wish you a merry Christmas if you're
listening to this around Christmas time
and thank you all for listening and I'll
talk to you on the next episode of
listening
[Music]
time